<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</title>
    <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Pentecost</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/pentecost-celebration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/pentecost-celebration/</guid>
      <description>Pentecost had a more special place in our family calendar this year, as we tried to truly bring the feast to life. And what a great joy it was to prepare a dwelling place for the Holy Spirit, as we anticipated His coming for the nine days since the Ascension.
Guided by the Spirit The Third Person of the Trinity can seem so abstract and volatile, difficult to grasp. I had to sit back in quietude to become more aware of His place in my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motherhood, May, and Mary</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/motherhood-mary-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/motherhood-mary-may/</guid>
      <description>No matter what comes along next, remember you are and always will be a mother.
These words I heard from my husband on the evening we made the sweetest discovery… of our little baby’s life, slowly growing inside me. Those first weeks were something of a surreal wonder at the miracle of Creation, but there was also a vague, hardly distinguishable anxiety. The enormous gift we had been entrusted with at the same time appeared so fragile and uncertain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man’s search for meaning, by Viktor Frankl – an unforgettable testimony of survival</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/frankl-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/frankl-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>As a future psychotherapist, and writer of WWII fiction, I’ve been drawn for a while towards discovering Viktor Frankl’s work. I did not know much about his school of psychoanalysis, apart from the fact that his experiences from Auschwitz and other concentration camps were a catalyzer in the birth of logotherapy.
Man’s search for meaning offers a vivid image of the endurance of the human spirit in the face of adversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Generation of “Columbuses” – witnesses of a fulfilled apocalypse</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kolumbowie-poets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kolumbowie-poets/</guid>
      <description>I remember sitting in a Polish literature class early on in high school, hearing for the first time the story of Krzysztof Kamil Baczyński. The young talented poet who fought in the Warsaw Uprising, tragically killed at the age of 23. Immediately, I fell in love with this symbolic figure, merging the age-old themes of love and death. Little did I know that his verses would inspire the title of my first novel years later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “Silent and Dark” – Cichociemni – elite of the Polish resistance</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/cichociemni-parachuters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/cichociemni-parachuters/</guid>
      <description>Largo House, Fife, Scotland. Out of sight of villager passersby stands an abandoned edifice, overgrown with bushes and trees. A labyrinth of fences, fields and barbed wires must be crossed before reaching the deserted premises. But in the 1940s, the lost in-the-middle-of-nowhere hidden nature of this place was perfectly suited to its purposes.
Largo House, past and present Decades ago, these grounds were the training center of the 1st Independent Polish Parachute Brigade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Warsaw Uprising – 79 years</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/warsaw-uprising-79-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/warsaw-uprising-79-years/</guid>
      <description>August 1st, 5.00pm.
Every year, for one minute, the city of Warsaw freezes. The sound of sirens reverberates across the heavy summer air. Gathered in contemplation, we look back to those who, in 1944 at that same hour, initiated a battle to liberate their beloved city and homeland.
The Warsaw Uprising. 63 days of perseverance, honor, and bloodshed. Fighting to their last breath, Varsovians watched their home crumble to ruins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemorating victims of Volhynia - 80 years</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/wolyn-80-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/wolyn-80-years/</guid>
      <description>July 11th marks Poland’s National Day of Remembrance of the Volhynia massacre. This year, we commemorated 80 years from the tragic Krwawa Niedziela (“bloody Sunday”) - culmination point of a mass extermination action against Polish civilians, led by the Ukraine Nationalistic units OUN and UPA.
This cruel episode from the Second World War is little spoken of today. Approaching it is intimidating, especially in these times when Ukraine is fighting again, rightfully defending its territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executing the SS head - Operation Kutschera</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kutscheradiversionaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kutscheradiversionaction/</guid>
      <description>February 1st, 1944
Halfway through their ride across the bridge, the two young men noticed a blockade formed by German police on the opposite edge. The blood-covered car with gunshot marks would immediately unmask them… Retreat to the right bank? A panicked attempt to maneuver their way out, but the machine unexpectedly stalls. The agitated turning about did not go unnoticed. Already, German policemen start running towards them. Danger is also arising from the other side – first, the sound of gunshots, then the sight of even more uniformed figures… The men hurry out of the car, feverishly shooting around themselves in defense, throwing a last grenade into the crowd of soldiers approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyrical Croatian Adventures</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/travelcroatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/travelcroatia/</guid>
      <description>It began simply as a family visit, to a country I saw as overrated among tourists – growing up in Poland I never stopped hearing about people’s holidays in Croatia. At the time the destination seemed quite attractive, but with the years my interest faded away, until a new motivation appeared – to walk the roads along which many of my husband’s childhood summers were scattered.
So we waved goodbye to Scotland to discover a new destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attachment and Loss in Wartime</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/attachmenttheorywar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/attachmenttheorywar/</guid>
      <description>With a background in developmental psychology, I sometimes feel an implicit pressure to make scientific knowledge shine in my work as a writer. Do I ever achieve that goal? Perhaps not directly, but back in my final year of university I definitely enjoyed applying developmental theories to my characters… That was a good motivation to study! One of the topics that has fascinated me since the start of my journey with psychology is attachment theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scouts&#39; Resistance - Szare Szeregi</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/polishscoutswar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/polishscoutswar/</guid>
      <description>As a teenager in Poland, I was part of the Scouting movement, which through its ideals and lifestyle, left a profound impact on who I grew up to be. The values helped me in supporting my faith and moral framework, even in the shakier times of adolescence, when every voice around you seems to be calling for rebellion. Oftentimes people associate scouts simply with an image of kids running around the forest playing games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a novel - a step into Warsaw&#39;s past</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/inspirationfornovel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/inspirationfornovel/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;&amp;gt; (weight = 10) Since childhood, the history of my hometown has profoundly impacted my imagination. Wandering around the streets of Warsaw, every footstep was permeated by the weight of the past, the scars left on the city during the Second World War. A city once enslaved by the German Nazi invaders, its buildings still carry the impressions, both tangible and invisible, of fervent combat. I remember developing a fascination for a symbol depicted on countless memorial plaques and walls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whispers of Defiance</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/stories/shortstorywar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/stories/shortstorywar/</guid>
      <description>October 1939
The prison wagon was overcrowded with Polish soldiers. They were held in the dark as to their destination. Having been passed from the hands of the Russians to the Germans, they wondered which of the two evils to fear more.
Sebastian shut his eyes, trying to catch up on the rest and sleep he had been deprived of in the previous days. Slowly, the continuous murmurs faded away, and he saw once again his hometown, Warsaw, the loving faces left behind…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I am an emerging writer of historical fiction and a psychology graduate, currently based in Glasgow. Born to Polish parents, I grew up moving between France, Poland, and the U.S. Across these experiences, I discovered that my heart would always be most attached to the city of Warsaw, where I spent 10 years immersed in its breathtaking history. In my first novel, Dust of Wrathful Years, I attempt to give a glimpse into Poland’s heritage, through the stories of young people fighting for the country’s freedom during the Second World War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Book</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/my-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/my-book/</guid>
      <description>1939⁣. Childhood is cut short by the outbreak of war. After a short-lived era of renaissance, Poland is once again being torn to pieces. The endless struggle for freedom returns.
Aniela, Jadzia and Kamil were simply adolescents growing up in a promising age of renewal. Part of a generation born with their homeland’s independence, they were to discover Poland as a free and thriving country… Only to later discover death and destruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shop</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/shop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/shop/</guid>
      <description>Available now on Amazon. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
