<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WWII on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</title>
    <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/tags/wwii/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WWII on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/tags/wwii/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Man’s search for meaning, by Viktor Frankl – an unforgettable testimony of survival</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/frankl-search-for-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/frankl-search-for-meaning/</guid>
      <description>As a future psychotherapist, and writer of WWII fiction, I’ve been drawn for a while towards discovering Viktor Frankl’s work. I did not know much about his school of psychoanalysis, apart from the fact that his experiences from Auschwitz and other concentration camps were a catalyzer in the birth of logotherapy.
Man’s search for meaning offers a vivid image of the endurance of the human spirit in the face of adversity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Generation of “Columbuses” – witnesses of a fulfilled apocalypse</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kolumbowie-poets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kolumbowie-poets/</guid>
      <description>I remember sitting in a Polish literature class early on in high school, hearing for the first time the story of Krzysztof Kamil Baczyński. The young talented poet who fought in the Warsaw Uprising, tragically killed at the age of 23. Immediately, I fell in love with this symbolic figure, merging the age-old themes of love and death. Little did I know that his verses would inspire the title of my first novel years later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “Silent and Dark” – Cichociemni – elite of the Polish resistance</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/cichociemni-parachuters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/cichociemni-parachuters/</guid>
      <description>Largo House, Fife, Scotland. Out of sight of villager passersby stands an abandoned edifice, overgrown with bushes and trees. A labyrinth of fences, fields and barbed wires must be crossed before reaching the deserted premises. But in the 1940s, the lost in-the-middle-of-nowhere hidden nature of this place was perfectly suited to its purposes.
Largo House, past and present Decades ago, these grounds were the training center of the 1st Independent Polish Parachute Brigade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Warsaw Uprising – 79 years</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/warsaw-uprising-79-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/warsaw-uprising-79-years/</guid>
      <description>August 1st, 5.00pm.
Every year, for one minute, the city of Warsaw freezes. The sound of sirens reverberates across the heavy summer air. Gathered in contemplation, we look back to those who, in 1944 at that same hour, initiated a battle to liberate their beloved city and homeland.
The Warsaw Uprising. 63 days of perseverance, honor, and bloodshed. Fighting to their last breath, Varsovians watched their home crumble to ruins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemorating victims of Volhynia - 80 years</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/wolyn-80-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/wolyn-80-years/</guid>
      <description>July 11th marks Poland’s National Day of Remembrance of the Volhynia massacre. This year, we commemorated 80 years from the tragic Krwawa Niedziela (“bloody Sunday”) - culmination point of a mass extermination action against Polish civilians, led by the Ukraine Nationalistic units OUN and UPA.
This cruel episode from the Second World War is little spoken of today. Approaching it is intimidating, especially in these times when Ukraine is fighting again, rightfully defending its territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executing the SS head - Operation Kutschera</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kutscheradiversionaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kutscheradiversionaction/</guid>
      <description>February 1st, 1944
Halfway through their ride across the bridge, the two young men noticed a blockade formed by German police on the opposite edge. The blood-covered car with gunshot marks would immediately unmask them… Retreat to the right bank? A panicked attempt to maneuver their way out, but the machine unexpectedly stalls. The agitated turning about did not go unnoticed. Already, German policemen start running towards them. Danger is also arising from the other side – first, the sound of gunshots, then the sight of even more uniformed figures… The men hurry out of the car, feverishly shooting around themselves in defense, throwing a last grenade into the crowd of soldiers approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scouts&#39; Resistance - Szare Szeregi</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/polishscoutswar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/polishscoutswar/</guid>
      <description>As a teenager in Poland, I was part of the Scouting movement, which through its ideals and lifestyle, left a profound impact on who I grew up to be. The values helped me in supporting my faith and moral framework, even in the shakier times of adolescence, when every voice around you seems to be calling for rebellion. Oftentimes people associate scouts simply with an image of kids running around the forest playing games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a novel - a step into Warsaw&#39;s past</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/inspirationfornovel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/inspirationfornovel/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;&amp;gt; (weight = 10) Since childhood, the history of my hometown has profoundly impacted my imagination. Wandering around the streets of Warsaw, every footstep was permeated by the weight of the past, the scars left on the city during the Second World War. A city once enslaved by the German Nazi invaders, its buildings still carry the impressions, both tangible and invisible, of fervent combat. I remember developing a fascination for a symbol depicted on countless memorial plaques and walls.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
