<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</title>
    <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating a novel - a step into Warsaw&#39;s past</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/inspirationfornovel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/inspirationfornovel/</guid>
      <description>Since childhood, the history of my hometown has profoundly impacted my imagination. Wandering around the streets of Warsaw, every footstep was permeated by the weight of the past, the scars left on the city during the Second World War. A city once enslaved by the German Nazi invaders, its buildings still carry the impressions, both tangible and invisible, of fervent combat. I remember developing a fascination for a symbol depicted on countless memorial plaques and walls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executing the SS head - Operation Kutschera</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kutscheradiversionaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kutscheradiversionaction/</guid>
      <description>February 1st, 1944
Halfway through their ride across the bridge, the two young men noticed a blockade formed by German police on the opposite edge. The blood-covered car with gunshot marks would immediately unmask them… Retreat to the right bank? A panicked attempt to maneuver their way out, but the machine unexpectedly stalls. The agitated turning about did not go unnoticed. Already, German policemen start running towards them. Danger is also arising from the other side – first, the sound of gunshots, then the sight of even more uniformed figures… The men hurry out of the car, feverishly shooting around themselves in defense, throwing a last grenade into the crowd of soldiers approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyrical Croatian Adventures</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/travelcroatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/travelcroatia/</guid>
      <description>It began simply as a family visit, to a country I saw as overrated among tourists – growing up in Poland I never stopped hearing about people’s holidays in Croatia. At the time the destination seemed quite attractive, but with the years my interest faded away, until a new motivation appeared – to walk the roads along which many of my husband’s childhood summers were scattered.
So we waved goodbye to Scotland to discover a new destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attachment and Loss in Wartime</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/attachmenttheorywar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/attachmenttheorywar/</guid>
      <description>With a background in developmental psychology, I sometimes feel an implicit pressure to make scientific knowledge shine in my work as a writer. Do I ever achieve that goal? Perhaps not directly, but back in my final year of university I definitely enjoyed applying developmental theories to my characters… That was a good motivation to study! One of the topics that has fascinated me since the start of my journey with psychology is attachment theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Scouts&#39; Resistance - Szare Szeregi</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/polishscoutswar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/polishscoutswar/</guid>
      <description>As a teenager in Poland, I was part of the Scouting movement, which through its ideals and lifestyle, left a profound impact on who I grew up to be. The values helped me in supporting my faith and moral framework, even in the shakier times of adolescence, when every voice around you seems to be calling for rebellion. Oftentimes people associate scouts simply with an image of kids running around the forest playing games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whispers of Defiance</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/stories/shortstorywar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/stories/shortstorywar/</guid>
      <description>October 1939
The prison wagon was overcrowded with Polish soldiers. They were held in the dark as to their destination. Having been passed from the hands of the Russians to the Germans, they wondered which of the two evils to fear more.
Sebastian shut his eyes, trying to catch up on the rest and sleep he had been deprived of in the previous days. Slowly, the continuous murmurs faded away, and he saw once again his hometown, Warsaw, the loving faces left behind…</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
