<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Faith on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</title>
    <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/tags/faith/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Faith on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/tags/faith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autumn with Anne of Green Gables</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/autumn-anne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/autumn-anne/</guid>
      <description>“I’m so glad I live in a world where there are Octobers.” – Anne of Green Gables
Something about autumn fills me with childhood nostalgia… This year it inspired me to reread a favorite book after 13 years… For what is a good children’s book if not one that can be enjoyed in adulthood?
My love for Anne of Green Gables began when I was 12, about the same age as the heroine at the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First steps as a mother</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/first-steps-motherhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/first-steps-motherhood/</guid>
      <description>How can I even capture this time into words?
The intense joy in those first moments. Dazed and exhausted after hours of labor, I stepped into a new world. She’s here. Our daughter. I’ll never forget the moment I picked her up from the birth pool and held her in my arms. My first words to her. Kocham Cię Anielko. I love you, Aniela.
But after those initial exhilarating sparks came the inevitable exhaustion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June and the Most Sacred Heart</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/june-sacred-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/june-sacred-heart/</guid>
      <description>June has always carried a unique sweetness. Long summer days, eating as many strawberries as possible, loud but warm thunderstorms, the scent of elderflower soaked by rain&amp;hellip; My favorite time of the year for long strolls around town. Across the half-open church doors, I hear voices singing the litany to the Sacred Heart…
During my summers in Warsaw, every evening I would try to find a daily Mass followed by June devotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Pentecost</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/pentecost-celebration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/pentecost-celebration/</guid>
      <description>Pentecost had a more special place in our family calendar this year, as we tried to truly bring the feast to life. And what a great joy it was to prepare a dwelling place for the Holy Spirit, as we anticipated His coming for the nine days since the Ascension.
Guided by the Spirit The Third Person of the Trinity can seem so abstract and volatile, difficult to grasp. I had to sit back in quietude to become more aware of His place in my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motherhood, May, and Mary</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/motherhood-mary-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/motherhood-mary-may/</guid>
      <description>No matter what comes along next, remember you are and always will be a mother.
These words I heard from my husband on the evening we made the sweetest discovery… of our little baby’s life, slowly growing inside me. Those first weeks were something of a surreal wonder at the miracle of Creation, but there was also a vague, hardly distinguishable anxiety. The enormous gift we had been entrusted with at the same time appeared so fragile and uncertain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
