<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>War on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</title>
    <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/tags/war/</link>
    <description>Recent content in War on Klara Łuczka-Hanzalová</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/tags/war/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The “Silent and Dark” – Cichociemni – elite of the Polish resistance</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/cichociemni-parachuters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/cichociemni-parachuters/</guid>
      <description>Largo House, Fife, Scotland. Out of sight of villager passersby stands an abandoned edifice, overgrown with bushes and trees. A labyrinth of fences, fields and barbed wires must be crossed before reaching the deserted premises. But in the 1940s, the lost in-the-middle-of-nowhere hidden nature of this place was perfectly suited to its purposes.
Largo House, past and present Decades ago, these grounds were the training center of the 1st Independent Polish Parachute Brigade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Warsaw Uprising – 79 years</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/warsaw-uprising-79-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/warsaw-uprising-79-years/</guid>
      <description>August 1st, 5.00pm.
Every year, for one minute, the city of Warsaw freezes. The sound of sirens reverberates across the heavy summer air. Gathered in contemplation, we look back to those who, in 1944 at that same hour, initiated a battle to liberate their beloved city and homeland.
The Warsaw Uprising. 63 days of perseverance, honor, and bloodshed. Fighting to their last breath, Varsovians watched their home crumble to ruins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemorating victims of Volhynia - 80 years</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/wolyn-80-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/wolyn-80-years/</guid>
      <description>July 11th marks Poland’s National Day of Remembrance of the Volhynia massacre. This year, we commemorated 80 years from the tragic Krwawa Niedziela (“bloody Sunday”) - culmination point of a mass extermination action against Polish civilians, led by the Ukraine Nationalistic units OUN and UPA.
This cruel episode from the Second World War is little spoken of today. Approaching it is intimidating, especially in these times when Ukraine is fighting again, rightfully defending its territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executing the SS head - Operation Kutschera</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kutscheradiversionaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/kutscheradiversionaction/</guid>
      <description>February 1st, 1944
Halfway through their ride across the bridge, the two young men noticed a blockade formed by German police on the opposite edge. The blood-covered car with gunshot marks would immediately unmask them… Retreat to the right bank? A panicked attempt to maneuver their way out, but the machine unexpectedly stalls. The agitated turning about did not go unnoticed. Already, German policemen start running towards them. Danger is also arising from the other side – first, the sound of gunshots, then the sight of even more uniformed figures… The men hurry out of the car, feverishly shooting around themselves in defense, throwing a last grenade into the crowd of soldiers approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attachment and Loss in Wartime</title>
      <link>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/attachmenttheorywar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com/post/blog/attachmenttheorywar/</guid>
      <description>With a background in developmental psychology, I sometimes feel an implicit pressure to make scientific knowledge shine in my work as a writer. Do I ever achieve that goal? Perhaps not directly, but back in my final year of university I definitely enjoyed applying developmental theories to my characters… That was a good motivation to study! One of the topics that has fascinated me since the start of my journey with psychology is attachment theory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
